In KZ, Kansas City, Kansas, scientists are calling today's impact one of the most significant
astronomical events of the last century.
The enormous solar flare has already caused power surges and...
Clark!
Hey, Clark.
Son, you want to give us a hand here?
Yeah.
Sorry, I must have got sucked in.
You caught me in the middle of this news special.
Really?
What's the topic?
Solar flares and the effects on Earth's atmosphere.
According to NASA, the sun took a directive from a comet domain, causing one of the biggest
solar flares ever to be recorded.
Oh, you sound intrigued.
Actually, it's a relief to be researching NASA.
It's a cosmic disaster that has nothing to do with me.
I gotta go.
I told Pete I'd meet him at the town to swap some notes.
You need a ride?
Oh, I think I'll ride.
Bye.
Precipitation of huge explosions with powerful, far-reached effects.
The shockwave from this type of CME is so strong that it smashes the Earth's magnetic field,
unleashing a geomagnetic storm.
In layman's terms, people should expect...
Do you believe that there are powers greater than we can...
You know, somewhere in the universe?
Sure.
Look, you mind if I switch back to the game?
Hmm.
That's one small step for man, one giant leap for the metropolis sharks.
To Littleville, Kansas, and all the little Kansassians in it.
Hmm.
One more.
Look, pal, we don't want any trouble here.
I think you might have had enough.
If you want trouble, you just try cutting me off.
Don't come back.
Small town friendly, my butt.
Hey, I wanna play.
Hey.
Prentice, you close the Fish sfx box cream.
No.
emerges itself and the
presents are just join in the pleasure.
Y...
No, I'm, I'm...
I'll find it.
I...
Yeah, I know, this deactivate...
Yeah, no, no, I have not been drinking.
Now, come!
You okay?
You pulled the door right off the car with your bare hands?
You walked right through the power lines.
You're a little drunk, Mr...
White.
Perry White.
Somebody save me.
Let your warm hands break right through.
Don't care how you feel.
Just stay, stay.
Come on.
I've been waiting for you.
I've made this whole world shine for you.
Just stay, stay.
Come on.
You're a little drunk, Mr. White.
Just stay, stay.
Come on.
Just stay.
dezeus.
Take it easy, Clark.
I misjudged my strength.
I just got off the phone with the hospital.
Seems your Mr. Perry White checked himself out late last night.
The paramedic said his breathalyzer was off the charts.
What do you think he saw, son?
Dad, he probably doesn't even remember my name.
Clark! Clark Kent!
Thank you.
Yeah.
Last time I saw you, you were frisbeeing the door off my car
and ignoring the high-voltage lines.
Mr. White?
I was trying to figure out which of the four Clarks I should be thanking
when they hold me off in the ambulance.
You must be Mr. Kent? Yes, I am.
Certainly glad you're feeling better.
Well, that's relative. My car is crunched.
This hillbilly cartoon you have as a sheriff
has suspended my driver's license on a DUI,
and my assignment editor is screaming for my head.
You're a reporter?
In a past life.
At the moment, I'm the advance man for X-Styles,
cable TV's one-stop for the paranormally inclined.
And what brings you here to Smallville?
Oh, I'm researching a piece about the meteor shower
and the bizarre phenomena that it spawned.
Don't tell me you believe any of that nonsense.
It's right up there with the tooth fairy.
Don't you need tools for a job like that?
Ah, Mr. White.
You really didn't come all this way just to thank me, did you?
No, I didn't.
I thought we should discuss a settlement.
A settlement?
I didn't off-road my car for laughs, Mr. Kent.
I swerved to miss your son.
Look, I'll make this easy on you.
I need a local who knows the territory to ferry me around.
You loan me Clark for a couple days, we'll call it even.
I'll be right back.
My father went for historical accuracy
when he had the mansion reconstructed,
but I was thinking of taking some liberties with the decor.
Move away from the artifacts and period pieces
and go with something more modern, even abstract.
Any thoughts, Doctor?
Only that I hope today's session would be more productive.
Mm.
I believe the psychological term for, uh,
refusing to accept the inevitable is denial.
And no amount of probing can uncover emotional issues that don't exist.
Now who's in denial?
Trust me, I have nothing to hide.
Then tell me about the island.
The fishermen who found you said you were raving about some imaginary enemy.
I was ill, suffering from malaria.
I saw your blood work, Lex.
There was no trace of disease.
But even some fictitious illness would not explain
your reluctance to discuss your conflicted feelings towards your father.
Until we understand that...
What I understand, Doctor,
is that Luther Corp's insurance carrier insisted that I submit
to five psychiatric therapy sessions.
So I've submitted.
And sadly, our final hour is up.
I'll miss our sessions.
tense espresso
Two meteor craters, that's it.
You don't wanna see anything else?
Blown out buildings and sinkholes are background, Clark.
Now I'm looking for substance.
Texture.
The human dimension.
Clark. Is everything all right?
Pete waited for you until after 10 o'clock last night.
Uh, it's a long story.
Hi. Perry White.
I'd like a triple cappuccino
and a couple of those glazed crullers
and...
an interview
with Smallville's very own CoverGirl.
What are you doing?
It's called getting the story.
Nothing fancy, Miss Lang.
Just a simple Q&A.
You know, uh, how's little Miss Meteor coping
14 years after the Big Bang?
Maybe this is a joke to you,
but my parents died that day.
And I'm sorry,
but that makes you newsworthy.
That's it. You're leaving.
What?
You know, either she talks to me now
or she faces the cameras in the morning.
Clark, I can't believe you're with this guy.
Lana. Maybe you should both leave.
You didn't tell me Lana was part of your agenda.
You didn't tell me you knew.
You knew her.
Hey, I'm sorry if I hurt your girlfriend's feelings,
but she's a legitimate source.
No, she's not anymore.
It doesn't work that way, Clark.
I still have to find faces to put on camera.
You know, your high school papers developed quite a rep
in the bug-eyed monster circles.
Why would you say that?
Because I did, like, three minutes of research
before I came to town?
Think the editor would know something about the meteor shower?
How would I know?
Principal authorizes new gym mats
by Clark Kent.
I know I was riveted.
I think we should go.
Boy, I thought our stuff was off the wall.
This is incredible.
It's also all true.
Chloe, Mr. White is interested in the meteor shower.
I didn't think it would hurt if he had a look.
I have nothing to hide.
Oh, good.
I think we've already borrowed two or three of your ideas
for our show.
Now, do you make it all up yourself
or do you pull in other writers?
Excuse me?
Oh, just professional curiosity.
It's not every day that I meet another junk journalist
with a penchant for the bizarre.
Ex-stiles?
Yeah.
I have a penchant for the truth,
something your Freaks and Shrieks cable show
gave up around episode two.
That's it. We're done.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
You're the penchant for the truth.
You're the Perry White?
It's okay, Clark.
I'm gonna hoof it back to the motel.
You young lovers patch things up,
and then later on you can swing by
and we'll pick up the tour, hm?
Clark, do you have any idea who that was?
Greg?
No, I don't.
glen, glen, and neh?
Mm-hmm.
We'll see.
hell...
él
Is Oyife going on coisas friend?
No, I'm waiting to die with the boy.
You mean to eat JAYVIA's girlfriend?
Wouldn't you ask her, man?
about what happened every day.
And I'm sure you didn't come all this way to discuss that.
What did you want to see me about?
This tabloid television reporter came by the town today,
and he wanted to do an interview with me about the meteor shower.
A succinct no comment didn't dissuade him?
Not really.
He said he was going to come back tomorrow,
this time with a camera crew.
No.
Then you don't want that.
I've spent the last 14 years trying to put that day behind me,
and in an instant, he brought it all back.
I know it's a lot to ask,
but I was hoping that you might be able to do something.
I'm surprised you didn't go to Clark with this.
Clark's with him.
So you want me to run him out of town?
I want him to stop.
He must have been very persistent.
What was his name?
Perry White.
I'll make sure he never bothers you again.
Mr. White, I've been looking for you.
And here I am.
You may have the makings of a reporter yet, Kent.
Like you used to be.
Chloe and I did some checking after you left.
Memories fade, but a Google search never forgets.
And another drink isn't going to erase the fact
that you used to be one of the best reporters in Metropolis.
What happened?
Life isn't always perfect.
It's always not.
a journey, Grasshopper.
And sometimes a trip is smoother with a little lubricant.
What's it to you anyway?
Maybe it's the journalist in me.
Or that I realized if you have a gift,
you shouldn't turn your back on it.
Hm.
Made exactly two mistakes in my life, kid.
The first was getting into journalism.
What was the second?
Thinking it mattered.
One more.
No, he's had enough.
I don't get you, kid.
Strong-armed your parents, picked on your girlfriend,
and ticked off your lady editor.
Still, here you are, trying to play the hero.
Sometimes Clark's faith in his fellow man
outweighs his common sense.
Lex?
It's all right, Clark.
I'll deal with Mr. White from here.
I may have underestimated you, kid.
Clark doesn't have anything to do with this.
Look, Lex, if this is your old man's idea,
tell him I got the message back in Metropolis.
I have no intention of revisiting the past.
This isn't about my father, White.
It's about you.
Well, Lex, don't you think you're overreacting?
Considering the way he went after Lana,
I thought you'd admire my restraint.
Let's go.
Thanks for the ride, kid.
Oh.
You know, this get out of Dodge routine
is pretty heavy handed, even for a Luther.
So is ambushing a teenage girl for a sound bite.
Of course, using people always came easy to you.
You know?
The one and only encounter was years ago.
Even in boarding school, I was good at sniffing out reporters.
But you played the just a friendly conversation
card remarkably well.
As I recall, it was a full 10 minutes
before I told you to go to hell.
I was just doing my job.
And you were a legitimate source.
I was 16, and you were scrounging
for dirt on my father.
That's what this is really about, isn't it?
Your father's secrets.
If you really had anything on him, it would have come out
then.
If you actually believe that, I almost feel sorry for you.
Just make sure you're on the 4 o'clock, boss.
Well, so much for not drinking before 5.
Yeah.
I'm going to go.
Hey, Dad.
Hey.
Hey, Clark.
I wasn't expecting you until later.
Where's Mr. White?
He left.
I think he realized that Smallville wasn't quite as
friendly as he first thought.
Well, I'm glad you're here.
I've been trying to wrestle this thing up on a block
for about an hour.
You want to give me a hand?
Sure.
What's the matter?
I don't know.
It's like I've lost all my strength.
Why don't you give it one more try?
This place is full of Alicia.
Oh, my goodness.
I love you, dad.
I like you two.
I love you.
I like you.
I know, Dad.
Stop.
Look.
Hey, pay me a favor.
Fine.
I want to make up.
I'll call the neighborhood sheriff,
and get myoung at dat door.
Is there something that you can do to his soul, late?
Do you know anything?
Mr. Kent, you want to tell me how your tractor wound up scattered over Tulane's accounting
blacktop?
Yeah, we were pulling up to the farm in our truck and we saw somebody had put it on
the back of a flatbed.
So you're saying that someone was stealing it?
Well, I tried to follow them.
By the time I got here, it must have fallen off their truck.
I'm telling you, it fell out of the sky.
And last night you were begging the nurses to keep the flying monkeys out of your room.
Kid, you're saying you had nothing to do with this.
To be honest, Sheriff, I'm not sure what happened.
He's hiding something, Chief.
Mr. White, there's another bus in the back of the truck.
In about an hour.
I suggest you catch it.
Don't call me Chief.
Dad, I'm really sorry about the tractor.
It's a total loss.
Mark, I'm not concerned about the tractor.
Whatever's going on with your abilities, our family's wound up smack dab in the middle
of Perry White's radar.
Come on.
Why is Decision coming inside?
Weather service expects a light shower of threshing machines followed by a drizzle of
combines.
Guess I deserve that.
If you let me know what you're looking for, I'm sure I can help you find it.
Why would you want to do that?
Because you were once the kind of reporter that I would like to be.
Though I'm curious how one goes from multiple Pulitzer nominations to walking the Bigfoot
beat.
You know the only thing that's worse than never landing that story of a lifetime?
What?
Having it and being afraid to write it.
Perry the Pitbull White backing off a story?
That's hard to believe.
Well, Lionel Luther can be remarkably persuasive.
Are you saying he had something to do with your career slide?
Let's just say that not everyone respects good investigative journalism,
especially when it treads on the toes of the rich and vengeful.
Isn't that the Kent farm?
Good eye.
The police chalked it up to hyperactive frat boys going crop circles on the barn.
Why?
Call it professional interest.
Your friend Clark intrigues me.
We've thrown some Hail Marys in the past,
but to think that your problems have anything to do with a solar flare?
It's a bit of a stretch, don't you think?
I know, Dad, but my power started to glitch when the comet impacted.
Maybe there's a connection.
Make that probably.
Did you find something?
Yes.
Yesterday's cosmic fender bender produced a lot of light.
It's the largest solar flare ever recorded.
I'm talking communication glitches, power surges.
That's exactly what's been happening to me.
One second I'm helpless, and the next I'm in overdrive.
Well, we always have wondered about the source of your abilities.
Maybe my strength and my speed.
All the things I can do, they come from the sun.
It's like you're some sort of walking solar battery.
According to this, the effects of the solar flare ought to be done by tomorrow night.
Now, if that's true, maybe your accidents are going to stop.
As long as I don't use my abilities till then, we should be okay.
I'm not sure I'm going to be able to do that.
Hey, Clark!
I thought I'd give you a heads up.
Our resident Ghostbuster is still on the job.
Perry White?
I thought he went back to Metropolis.
Evidently he had a change of heart.
And he seems to be especially interested in you, Clark.
What the hell are you trying to do?
Lex, calm down.
Why?
You've already made up your mind about my so-called mental illness.
According to this, you're refusing to sign off on my psychological release.
In fact,
you're recommending even more sessions to be continued on an indefinite basis.
I have an ethical obligation to report my conclusions honestly.
Or maybe the nothing, shrink from Metropolis
wanted a little more face time with her celebrity patient.
You must be loving this.
I took no pleasure in my recommendation.
Then how do you explain it?
I think you need help, Lex.
Between the island, your failed marriage
that's happened since you came to Smallville.
You have experienced incredible emotional and physical trauma.
And your prescription's more time on the couch?
We just spent five sessions exploring my psyche.
No, we spent five hours discussing your art collection,
your fascination with expensive cars,
everything except the most traumatic moments of your life.
Lex, if you don't let your demons out, they could consume you.
We've been over this, Doctor.
We haven't even scratched the surface.
This control freak thing might fool your father,
but did you really think you could snow me?
Lex, please...
Get out.
Get out!
Morning, Clark.
What are you doing here?
You inspired me.
If you've got a gift, you should use it. Remember?
You're drunk.
Maybe.
Nonetheless, I finally found my story.
For some insane reason, it's me.
Chloe told me. I don't think it's funny.
Well, it's not a joke, Clark. I got the facts to back it up.
What kind of facts are those?
The accident. The power lines.
Your magical appearance as your family's tractor drops out of the sky.
I explained that.
It fell off a truck.
That's not an explanation. That's a plan.
It's a punchline.
I spent the morning combing through police records and newspaper stories.
You're Johnny on the spot, Clark.
You're Smallville's own hero on deck.
Trust me, Mr. White, there's nothing special about me.
Oh, that's where you're wrong, kid.
So far, I got you pegged as really strong and shock-resistant.
Question is, what other tricks have you got up your sleeve?
Clark! Clark, could you give me a hand?
I've got to go.
I've been stonewalled by the best of them.
You can run, but you can't hide.
Clark, you all right, son?
It's been a weird day.
My light speed gave out on Lake Tahoe.
It's got to be a thousand miles.
I know.
One second I'm racing across the country, the next I can barely jog.
I tried to make it home.
My super speed gave out again around Colorado Springs.
I barely had enough money for a bus ticket.
This thing's getting way out of control, Clark.
Don't worry, Dad.
I am glued to the couch until the solar flare passes.
I'm afraid it's not going to be that easy, son.
Perry White saw you.
Perry White saw you disappear.
Now, your mother managed to get him off the farm, but I don't think he's going to give up.
Not that easy, anyway.
When they told me you were at the gate, I could hardly believe it.
Yeah, you and me both.
I just thought we should talk.
We have nothing to talk about.
Huh.
Sorry to hear that.
Now, I guess you'll never find out what I have on your father.
If it's personal, I don't care.
If it's legal, the statute of limitations must have passed long ago.
That depends.
This information is so damning.
Why did my father stop at simply destroying your career?
Multiple copies, plus multiple attorneys, all within the event of my death instructions to December 5, 1936.
You do the math.
It's all yours.
I just want one thing in return.
What did you have in mind?
Everything you know about Clark Kent.
Clark?
Yeah.
Two years ago, you drove your Porsche off a bridge.
I went over the police photos, Lex.
There's no way you could have walked away from that crash without the miracle that is Clark Kent.
Imagine my surprise when I discovered that you'd been caught.
I'm sure you'd be surprised.
I don't know.
I was surprised when I discovered that you'd actually cultivated a friendship with this kid.
So now you're going after Clark.
This is a new low, even for you.
The Lex I knew wouldn't shake your hand without an ulterior motive.
You must have something.
Give it to me, and I'll deliver you a story that'll bring new meaning to the phrase,
Sins of the Father.
Ow!
You may have been able to neutralize my father, but not me.
Looks like the jungle living really took a toll.
principal
I'm warning you.
Stay away from me and stay away from my friends.
Trust me.
There won't be any blood on my hands when they find what's left of you.
.
Clark, I never thought you'd rate your own paparazzi.
Perry White must have called in a million favors to get a camera crew.
Yeah.
Well, the good news is there's only one,
and if the solar flare theory's correct,
then your tractor-tossing days will be over by tonight.
I don't believe this.
I can't believe this.
I feel like a prisoner in my own house.
I just...
Clark?
Pete, get down!
Mom! Dad!
Clark, wait!
Johnson, hurry!
Son!
Clark, get back!
Dad!
Clark.
What's wrong with your hand?
I burned it.
My powers, they must be gone again.
Clark, remember, all you have to do is get through today.
And hope that I don't get another solar flare burst
and burn the farm down.
Next time I could hurt you or Mom,
and Perry White will be there to catch the whole thing on tape.
Dad, I can't stay here.
I can't stay here.
Come straight into that.
This home is mine.
You can come by,
but I've got to say this now.
There's no such thing as love abroad.
I don't wish for anything but love,
and I just wish for the best for them.
This home is mine.
Clark!
Wait, Eric.
It's all right, gee.
If you're going to make it,
be happy,
and you're going to have your dream best story,
I'm going to spend a президkenenanium life.
That's not what you'reacionally going to do.
You've gotta try to do your job well',
and you're a great, great father.
You hard-hearted man.
Dad, we worked hard.
Keep it rolling. I want it all on tape.
Clark is not here.
And he's not coming back until you people are gone.
So why don't you just leave my family alone?
Come on, Clark. They're long gone.
Thanks for doing all this, Pete.
You know I'm always up for a little undercover brother.
So we'll camp out tonight.
Check in with your parents in the morning.
We reserve the right to refuse service to anyone.
I think you'd be more comfortable
throwing your hands up.
You're a wild coyote.
Oh, I was until they threw me out.
Either way, I'd like you to leave.
Please, Miss Lang.
Sometimes I let my enthusiasm
for a story outweigh my good sense.
Is that your idea of an apology?
No, look, look.
Okay, okay, okay. I'm a jerk.
And I've got the broken engagements
and the sleepless nights
to prove it.
If your job bothers you so much,
why don't you stop?
Because I'm a journalist.
It's in my blood.
And sometimes you have to push
to get the truth,
even when it hurts.
Well, if you're finished,
I'm gonna call you a cab.
It won't come.
It's a little issue
over non-payment affairs.
But I'll make you a deal.
Oh, Mr. White.
I will trade permanently
staying out of your life
for a ride to the bus stop.
Let me get my coat.
Hello?
Lana?
What?
No, don't do anything.
I'll be right there.
Clark, what's going on?
I gotta get to Saunders Gorge
right now.
Your speed thing's still out?
I got nothing, Pete.
It's all gone.
Get in.
I'll drive.
I got nothing, Pete.
Get in.
Go!
Come on, are you okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
I was driving him to the bus stop, and he pretended to be sick.
Pulled over, and he ran out to the viewpoint and got out on the ledge
and said he would kill himself unless I called you.
Look, Clark, be careful. He's really drunk.
Look, none less iced tea packs a punch.
I knew you'd never show for me, so I had to trick Lana into making the call.
Mr. White, don't do this.
See, the way I figure it, you're strong, you're shockproof,
and you're incredibly fast.
Plus, you're cursed with this hero complex.
Yeah, why don't you come back down on the deck, and we'll talk about that.
No, not until I have my story.
Wait, Mr. White.
Look, you're wrong about me.
I'm betting you'll save me, Clark.
No, I can't save you.
Well, I guess we'll find out, huh?
No!
Okay, fun's over.
Time to unleash those incredible powers.
Let's go.
Here, Clark.
I don't have any powers!
Pete!
The camping gear! There should be a rope!
Okay.
Hold on, Mr. White!
Hurry!
Kid!
Ah!
Pete, it's not gonna hold!
Come on!
Grab the rope!
Hang on, kid.
Ah!
Hold on!
Hang on, kid!
Oh!
Go!
Yeah.
!
Fine.
Good!
You're doing!
Aah!
Ah!
Oh!
Come on!
Ah!
DIE!
Die!
Use your weapons!
Ah!
Hurry!
All right now.
Get it off!
It's longer!
relationship!
Get moving!
Here, give me your hand.
Here.
Oh, Clark.
I'm sure you understand the need for confidentiality.
I will be revealing things that are deeply personal, even hurtful.
That's the point of therapy, Lex. To regain control.
Let the bad feelings go and start recovering from the traumas of the past.
Then tomorrow, 10 a.m.
Clark, breakfast is almost ready.
Great. I'll be done in a second.
So, you're sure everything's okay now?
Once the effects of the solar flare faded, everything went back to normal.
Including your sense of humor.
Hi, Lana.
This is a surprise.
Mrs. Kent, I hope I didn't come at a bad time.
No, not at all. Clark, I'll keep a plate warm for you.
I'll be right back.
Bye.
Hey, Lana.
You know, I was gonna stop by the Talon later.
Just... all the craziness. I didn't get a chance to thank you.
Well, I still don't understand why Mr. White thought you could do all those incredible things.
But I'm glad I was able to help.
Yeah, I wasn't just talking about the gorge.
Whether I meant to or not, I helped judge up all your old memories about the meter show.
I wanted to thank you for forgiving me.
Well, that's part of the reason why I came by.
I went to the graveyard this morning.
But your parents were happy to see you.
Suddenly I realized I hadn't been there for months.
At first I felt guilty.
You know, like I'd done something wrong.
But then I realized that...
that is the last thing I can do.
I'm sorry.
But then I realized that...
that is the last thing they would have ever wanted for me.
So what did you tell them?
The truth.
That I never meant to ignore them.
But...
there's someone else in my life now.
Someone I really care about.
Lana...
Clark...
It's okay.
I also told them that we were in a kind of strange place right now.
But I'm still hoping that we can work it out.
The important thing is...
they know they will always be in my thoughts.
Better go.
Totally.
And...
I want to go to see them.
Alan!
Alan, Alan!
Yes Angel?
Any instant definition?
You've got a derrière the scenes.
Awesome.
Don't ruin your life.
This mean nothing to you.
Thanks again for the ride.
It's the only way I could be sure you'd get on the bus.
What?
You really are kind of a freak, you know that?
Mr. White.
I'm serious.
You try to help people, even fools like me,
and you never ask for anything in return.
When I saw your face up there after it was all over,
I suddenly realized I was about to tear down a good person.
I just couldn't believe there was actually anyone like you out there.
Trust me, Mr. White, I'm not that good.
Well, I'm just glad nobody got hurt.
Chalk it up to hallucinations or the DTs.
All I know is I got a wake-up call.
Well, I am, uh, exactly 17 hours and 5 minutes sober.
I'm glad some good came out of all this.
So what's next?
Well, if you found the guts to go over that cliff,
maybe I can find the courage to finish the one story I let go.
Something tells me the world hasn't seen the last of Perry White.
Something tells me you're right.
Rumor has it I still have a friend or two on the Daily Planet.
Oh, uh, by the way, I, uh, I went over a couple more of your torch stories.
Yeah.
Well, they're rough, and half the time you bury the lead, but I see a glimmer of hope.
If you ever make the Metropolis, look me up.
I owe you one.
Yeah.
We've been in a lot of trouble for his mentioning and he's been good and labeled as a Ariel
President recently.
Yep.
Thank you.